Ricard Alcaraz Mancebo

Barcelona, Spain · https://www.linkedin.com/in/ricard-alcaraz-mancebo/ · +34 628 21 24 22 · ricard@ricard-alcaraz.com · ricard-alcaraz.com

Computer Engineer with 4 years of experience as a Cloud Data Engineer and Developer. I have a solid understanding of Economics and Management and I have worked as an external consultant for CaixaBank Tech.

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Seidor OpenTrends Barcelona, ES

Cloud Data Engineer / PMO Consultant

Nov 2023-Now

- Developed PMO process automations for CaixaBank Tech.
- Implemented CI/CD practices to enhance software delivery efficiency, reducing errors for CaixaBank Tech applications.
- Designed and developed a data analysis application on the Google Cloud Platform for CaixaBank Tech. Using technologies such as GCS, Airflow, DBT, BigQuery and Looker Core.

Ilimit Comunicacions S.L.

Terrassa, ES

Developer / R&D

Apr 2021-Jul 2022

- Designed a Proof of Concept (PoC) for a Blockchain-based application on the Bitcoin network.
- Developed a Blockchain-based application with a strong focus on innovation, primarily using Python, Vue.js, and Solidity.

Áser Reparapcs

Badia del Valles, ES

Web Developer / IT Technician

Feb 2017-Feb 2018

Developed two websites using WordPress and performed computer technician tasks.

EDUCATION

UAB - UPNA - UIB Barcelona-Pamplona, ES

University Master's Degree in Management, Organization and Business Economics (English)

2022-2023

Universitat Autònoma de Barcelona

Computer Engineering

Barcelona, ES 2017-2021

INS Badía del Vallés Badía del Vallés, ES

Web App Development

2015-2017

ADDITIONAL SKILLS

- Certification Google Associate Cloud Engineer
- Certification Google Project Management
- Course DBT + BigQuery
- Native in Spanish and Catalan. Fluent in English. Basic in Chinese.